# **Fuad Babayev**

# **Frontend Developer**

Baku

babayevffuad@gmail.com 050-743-19-51

https://www.linkedin.com/in/fuad-babayev-b8a649199

https://github.com/FuadBabayev

https://portfolio-fuadbabayev.netlify.app

### Summary

Web developer with more than one year of experience in Frontend Development. As a winner of Career Development Scholarship Program organized by Technest and Code Academy, I have successfully completed "Advanced Frontend Development" program with Honour Diploma. During education, I have contributed to several projects, ranging from e-commerce to admin dashboard systems, where I gained extensive knowledge of Figma, GitHub, HTML5, CSS3, SASS, Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, TypeScript, React, and Redux on the client side and MongoDB, Mongoose, Express, SQL, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Postman, NodeJS and PHP on the server side.

## Experience

#### Web Developer Internship — Goweb Creative Agency

June 2024 - Present

As an intern, I currently work on real websites and make changes to existing sites. This handson experience allows me to apply my skills in advanced development and strengthen my understanding of web technologies. In addition, I learn backend technologies such as PHP, MySQL and Laravel and apply these technologies to the websites I create on the Client Side

#### Frontend Developer Internship — GI Group

May 2024 - July 2024

- Creating the user interface and user experience (UI/UX) for Customer Relationship Management (CRM) systems using HTML, CSS, JavaScript and React
- Participate in agile development processes, such as sprint planning and daily stand-ups
- Partner with designers, backend developers, and product managers to bring features from concept to implementation

#### Frontend Developer Mentor — Evocoding Training Center

Oct 2023 – Dec 2023

I continued as a mentor at Evocoding Training Center after completing my studies with a high average. In my role as a mentor, I improved my ability to communicate with students and how to solve difficult problems for them. For me, teaching the new students was a positive experience.

#### Frontend Developer Internship — AZ Tech IT Solution

Oct 2023 – Nov 2023

- Created multiple responsive websites for mobile and desktop devices using HTML and CSS, as well as third-party libraries of JavaScript such as Query, and React
- Increasing my ability to operate as a team by closely collaborating with twelve other students
- Working with REST API using Postman

#### Academic advisor — Azerbaijan State Oil and Industry

May 2021 - June 2022

- Monitor students' attendance and progress
- Assist students to become independent and collaborative learners
- Guidance of up to 100 undergraduate students

#### **Achievements & Certificates**

Career Development Scholarship at Code Academy

Dec 2023 - May 2024

Honour Diploma of Completion Advanced Frontend Development

**Evocoding Training Center** 

June 2023 – Nov 2023

Certificate of Completion Front End Development

International Development Program (IDP)

Dec 2019 – Feb 2020

IELTS Score: 6.5/9

#### **Additional Information**

Languages: Azerbaijani (native), Turkish (native), English (intermediate), French (beginner),

Russian (pre-intermediate)

Frontend Development Tools: Figma, Git, Github, HTML5, CSS3, SASS, Bootstrap, Tailwind

CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, TypeScript, React, Router, Redux

Backend Development Tools: PHP, NodeJS, Express JS, Postman Relational Database Management System: SQL, MySQL, PostgreSQL

NoSQL Database: Mongo DB, Mongoose

#### **Education**

Advanced Frontend Development

Dec 2023 – May 2024

Career Development Scholarship Program | Technest and Code Academy

Master of Science

Sep 2020 - July 2022

Azerbaijan State Oil and Industry University | Research and Exploration of Oil and Gas fields.

**Bachelor of Science** 

Sep 2016 – July 2020

French-Azerbaijani University | Geophysical Engineering